Mragendra Singh C-137 New Ashok Nagar New Delhi-110096

Mob: 9555302784, 9555692256

Email: mragendra.singh90@gmail.com

#### CAREER OBJECTIVE

I am looking for a position in Human Resource Department in a reputed organization to contribute my skills and experience. I am having more than 8 years of experience in the field of HR. Experienced in man power planning, end to end recruitment, Joining Formalities, On boarding, Offer generation, documentation, Managing human resource system, Managing Payroll, Managing attendance & leaves, Vendor empanelment & management, Exit Interviews and Full & final settlement, Conducting employee welfare programs, employee grievance handling, Implementing HR policies etc.

#### AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Manpower Planning and end to end recruitment.
- Well versed with hiring channels like Naukri.com, Monster, Shine, Times Jobs, Linkedin, Wisdom jobs, Quikrjobs etc.
- Vendor empanelment & management.
- HR Policy Execution, PF & ESIC & Gratuity compliance.
- Maintaining Employee Relations.
- Managing entire cycle from new recruit to exit.

# KEY SKILLS

- Executing the HR plans and policies in conjunction with the company's overall development.
- Developing & executing the exit process for the employees.
- Dealing with the final settlement of employees when they leave.
- Maintaining good internal communication within the company.
- Responsible for working alongside operational managers to ensure all HR activities
- Posting positions through approved recruitment channels.
- Led the creation of recruiting plans for all open positions.
- Created and completed personnel action forms for all hires, terminations, title changes...
- Developed salary proposals for new recruits.
- Facilitated all new employee orientations to foster a positive team attitude.
- Screened all applicants based on their qualifications and background.
- Executing company-wide HR initiatives. Implementing talent acquisition strategies. Managing a team of 3 HR staff. Building relationships with third party recruitment agencies. Selection and induction activity for both permanent and temporary staff.
- Managing an effective employee performance review system. Microsoft Office (PowerPoint, Outlook, Word, Excel).
- Extensive knowledge of Human resource management system.
- Well versed with Campus recruitment.

# CORE COMPETENCIES

- Operating Systems: Windows 98/ Windows XP ,Windows 10
- MS Office, Tally.
- Giving new starters a really positive and professional perception of the company.
- Operationalising, integrating and delivering HR processes, projects and change.
- Driving excellence and best practise at every opportunity.
- IExecuting company-wide HR initiatives.
- Implementing talent acquisition strategies.
- Managing a team of over 3 HR staff.
- Building relationships with third party recruitment agencies. n charge of all recruitment, selection and induction activity for both permanent a temporary staff.

- Managing an effective employee performance review system.
- Establishing a proper organizational structure. Developing and implementing disciplinary policies.
- Developing and implementing employee welfare policies.
- Developing the exit process for the employees. Dealing with the final settlement of employees when they leave. Maintaining good internal communication within the company.
- Developing various reports for management, which make it easy to make decisions regarding the current resources.
- Responsible for working alongside operational managers to ensure all HR activities are carried out to the highest standard.Core competencies

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- > Assistant Manager HR -Dex Group-A chain of Airlines & Japanese Restaurant business (July 2019-Present)
- Handling entire recruitment cycle for Airline domain & Japanese cuisine restaurant.
- Documentation & on boarding.
- Payroll Management.
- Salary preparation & processing.
- Handling Statuary compliances related to PF, ESIC & Gratuity.
- Administration.
- Executing the HR plans and policies in conjunction with the company's overall development.
- Overall responsibility of man power planning and recruitments.
- Developing the induction programs for the new recruits.
- Coordinating with finance department for processing of payments to employees.
- Developing & executing the exit process for the employees.
- Dealing with the final settlement of employees when they leave.
- Maintaining good internal communication within the company.
- Responsible for working alongside operational managers to ensure all HR activities
- Posting positions through approved recruitment channels.

- > Assistant Manager HR-MS India (November 2017-June 2019)
- **➤ Assistant Manager HR Country Club India Ltd. (June 2016-September 2017)**
- Partnered with local organizations and universities for engagement and interest in jobs offered in their community.
- Vendor Empanalement.
- Vendor Management.
- Pre-screening all resumes prior to sending them to corporate hiring managers for consideration.
- Conducted exit interviews and verified that employment.
- Supported management in developing and implementing personnel policies and procedures.
- Organized new employee orientation schedules for all new hires.
- Coordinated meetings, developed meeting content and presented
- Promptly corresponded with all applicants and coordinated and conducted interviews.
- Made salary adjustments and managed contract renewals and promotions.
- Converted employee status from temporary to permanent...
- Managing an effective employee performance review system.
- Establishing a proper organizational structure. Implementing disciplinary policies.
- Conducting the exit process for the employees. Dealing with the final settlement of employees when they leave.
- Developing various reports for management, which make it easy to make decisions regarding the current resources.
- Responsible for working alongside operational managers to ensure all HR activities are carried out.
- **➢Brown Bird Pvt. Ltd:** Assistant Manager HR December 2014-May 2016
- > Country Club India Ltd.:-Executive HR, August 2012 November 2014

#### **EDUCATION**

- Obtained M.B.A(HR) from UP Technical University 2012
- Bachelor of Science Degree from M.J.P. Rohilkhand University, Bareilly -2010.
- 10<sup>th</sup> & 12<sup>th</sup> from UP Board.

# ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Proficient in Microsoft Office (PowerPoint, Outlook, Word, Excel, Access)
- Expert in Competitive Analysis and strong counseling and convincing
- Extensive knowledge of HRMS

Mragendra Singh